A Guide to the Nelson A. Rockefeller personal papers, Washington, DC, Series O FA350
Rockefeller Archive Center
- Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs, August 1940-December 1944; 1; 32.8 Cubic Feet
  - Office of the Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs (CIAA)
    - Mexico Builds a Democracy, c.1940s; Sound, Color, 20 min.; 16mm film (Reel AV 1298)
      Education programs for the Tarascan Indians; presented by Contemporary Films.
      File Plan
    - Mexico City, c.1940s; Sound, Color, 11 min.; 16mm film (Reel AV 1511)
      Access copy currently unavailable. Please contact an RAC archivist for further instruction.
      Tour of the city, narrated by Orson Welles; produced by the Mexican Tourism Department and Mitla Films
    - Montevideo Family, c.1940s; Sound, Black and white, 16 min.; 16mm film (Reel AV 1299)
      A day in the life of a typical middle class family; presented by Julien Bryan Productions.
    - Our Neighbors Down the Road, c.1940s; Sound, Color, 42 min.; 16mm film (Reel AV 1300)
      Scenic tour along the Pan-American Highway, through Venezuela, Argentina, and Brazil; produced by Herbert Lanks/Pan-American Highway Confederation.
    - La Paz, c.1940s; Sound, Black and white, 16 min.; 16mm film (Reel AV 1294)
      Footage of Indian market, folk dances, local architecture and construction; presented by Julien Bryan Productions.
    - Peru's Coastal Region, c.1940s; Sound, Color, 11 min.; 16mm film (Reel AV 1301)
      Travelogue discussing agriculture, geography, architecture, society, Incan culture, and related archaeological projects; narrated by Wendell C. Bennett.
    - Picturesque Patzcuaro, c.1940s; Sound, Color, 11 min.; 16mm film (Reel AV 1302)
      Narrated by Tyrone Power, produced by the Mexican Tourism Department
    - Que es Enfermedad (What is Disease?), 1945; Sound, Color, 11 min.; 16mm film (Box 2, Dvd AV 1303, Reel AV 1303)
      Animated feature from Walt Disney Studios, part of the "Health for the Americas" series.
    - Ramon Esta Enfermo (Ramon is Ill), c.1940s; Sound, Color, 11 min.; 16mm film (Box 2, Dvd AV 1304, Reel AV 1304)
      Animated feature from Walt Disney Studios, part of the "Reading for the Americas" series (# 4).
    - La Riqueza de los Andes (The Wealth of the Andes), c.1940s; Sound, Color, 28 min.; 16mm film (Reel AV 1305)
      History of Peru with a tour of Lima; footage of railroads, mines, hydroelectric plants; copper and lead smelting.
    - The Road to Cuernavaca, c.1940s; Sound, Color, 10 min,; 16mm film (Reel AV 1306)
      Travelogue produced by the Mexican Tourist Department: vacation resorts in Cuernavaca, Tasco, Acapulco; footage of murals by Diego Rivera; narrated by Tyrone Power.
    - Roads South, c.1940s; Sound, Black and white, 18 min.; 16mm film (Reel AV 1307)
      Transportation in South America; geographic obstacles; Pan American highway; presented by Julien Bryan Productions.
    - Saneamiento del Ambiente (Environmental Sanitation), 1945; Sound, Color, 8 min.; 16mm film (Box 2, Dvd AV 1308, Reel AV 1308)
      Animated feature about a growing community and its sanitation needs: water supply, waste management, etc.; presented by Walt Disney Studios, as part of the "Health in the Americas" series.
    - Sao Paulo, c.1940s; Sound, Black and white, 15 min.; 16mm film (Reel AV 1309)
      Overview of Sao Paulo history, growth, industries, and standards of living; presented by the Office of Strategic Services.
    - Schools to the South, c.1940s; Sound, Black and white, 13 min.; 16mm film (Reel AV 1310)
      Education in Latin America; presented by Julien Bryan Productions.
    - La Semilla de Oro (The Golden Grain), 1942; Sound, Color, 10 min.; 16mm film (Box 2, Dvd AV 1311, Reel AV 1311)
      Animated feature about the history and development of corn, the importance and usage of corn in the Mexican diet, and an introduction to related technology and science; presented by Walt Disney Studios.
    - South Chile, c.1940s; Sound, Black and white, 20 min.; 16mm film (Reel AV 1312)
      Visit to an Indian reservation, the Straits of Magellan, resorts, sheep ranches; presented by Julien Bryan Productions.
    - South of the Border with Disney, 1942; Sound, Color, 33 min.; 16mm film (Box 2, Dvd AV 1313, Reel AV 1313)
      Tour with Walt Disney, his wife, and Disney staff through South American countries to promote good will and collect material for films; scenes of Rio de Janeiro, Montevideo, Buenos Aires, Argentina, Mendoza, Chile, La Paz, Lake Titicaca, Guatemala, and Mexico City; presented by Walt Disney Studios.
    - Southern Brazil, c.1940s; Sound, Black and white, 20 min.; 16mm film (Reel AV 1314)
      Progress in Brazil from an agricultural to an industrial nation; produced by the Office of Strategic Services.
    - Tehauntepec, c.1940s; Sound, Color, 10 min.; 16mm film (Reel AV 1315)
      City scenery: women at the marketplace, costume and jewelry descriptions, weddings and festivals; produced by the Mexican Tourism Department, narrated by Linda Darnell.
    - A Town in Old Mexico, c.1940s; Sound, Color, 10 min.; 16mm film (Reel AV 1316)
      Visit to Puebla Fortin de las Flores, Orizaba; produced by the Mexican Tourism Department; narrated by Orson Welles.
    - La Tuberculosis, 1944; Sound, Color, 10 min.; 16mm film (Box 2, Dvd AV 1317, Reel AV 1317)
      Animated feature on the cause and treatment of Tuberculosis; produced by Walt Disney Studios.
    - Uncinariasis (Hookworm), 1945; Sound, Color, 10 min.; 16mm film (Box 2, Dvd AV 1318, Reel AV 1318)
      Animated feature on Hookworm: how it attacks, spreads, and develops, and how to prevent it. Produced by Walt Disney Studios.
    - Uruguay, c.1940s; Sound, Black and white, 18 min.; 16mm film (Reel AV 1319)
      Standards of living in Uruguay; explanation of government; presented by Julien Bryan Productions.
    - Yucatan: The Old Land of the Mayas, c.1940s; Sound, Color, 20 min.; 16mm film (Reel AV 1508)
      History of Merida and its industry; Mayan, Itza and Chichen temples; produced by the Mexican Tourism Department; narrated by Charles Bickford (English version).
    - Water: Friend or Enemy?, 1942; Sound, Color, 9 min.; 16mm film (Box 2, Dvd AV 1320, Reel AV 1320)
      Animated feature about the construction of wells to secure safe drinking water; presented by Walt Disney Studios.
    - The Winged Scourge, 1943; Sound, Color, 10 min.; 16mm film (Box 2, Dvd AV 1321, Reel AV 1321)
      Animated feature about protection against the anopheles mosquito with the Seven Dwarfs; presented by Walt Disney Studios.
    - Wings Over Brazil, c.1940s; Sound, Black and white, 15 min.; 16mm film (Reel AV 1322)
      From the Office of Strategic Services, a documentary about Brazilian aviation pioneers in the Air Academy. Includes footage from a naval airbase during wartime.
    - Young Uruguay, c.1940s; Sound, Black and white, 17 min.; 16mm film (Reel AV 1323)
      Schools, education and recreation in Uruguay; presented by Julien Bryan Productions.
  - General, 1940 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - General, 1941 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - General, 1942 (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - General, January-May 1943 (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - General, June-December 1943 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - General, 1944 (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - General, 1945 (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - General, 1946 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - General, January-May 1947 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - General, June 1947-June 1956 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Argentina, 1943-1945 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Background Material
    - Argentina, March 1943 - July 1944 (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Argentina, August-December 1944 (Box 2, Folder 13)
    - Argentina, 1945 (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Argentina, 1946 (Box 2, Folder 15)
    - Foreign Trade, 1940-1944 (Box 2, Folder 16)
    - Foreign Trade, 1945-1947 (Box 2, Folder 17)
    - Latin America, 1941-1942 (Box 3, Folder 18)
    - Latin America, 1943-1944 (Box 3, Folder 19)
    - Latin America, 1945-1948 (Box 3, Folder 20)
    - Latin American Nations (B-Ch), 1941-1947 (Box 3, Folder 21)
    - Latin American Nations (Co-Pan), 1941-1947 (Box 3, Folder 22)
    - Latin American Nations (Par-V), 1941-1947 (Box 3, Folder 23)
    - Post-War Planning, 1941-1945 (Box 3, Folder 24)
    - Post-War Planning, 1946-1948 (Box 4, Folder 25)
  - Advisory Committee, 1940-1941 (Box 4, Folder 26)
  - Moe Berg Report, 1944-1966 (Box 4, Folder 27)
  - British-Argentine Relations, 1944-1945 (Box 4, Folder 28)
  - Budget Figures, Miscellaneous, 1940-1947 (Box 4, Folder 29)
  - Brazil, 1942-1946 (Box 4, Folder 30)
  - Communications Study, 1942 (Box 4, Folder 31)
  - Confidential Projects, 1941-1942 (Box 4, Folder 32)
  - Congress, 1941-1944 (Box 4, Folder 33)
  - Coordination Committee, 1942-1945 (Box 4, Folder 34)
  - Cultural Relations, 1940-1944 (Box 5, Folder 35)
  - Division of Inter-American Activities in the United States, 1942-1944 (Box 5, Folder 36)
  - Donovan, William, 1941-1946 (Box 5, Folder 37)
  - NAR Draft Records, 1940-1945 (Box 5, Folder 38)
  - NAR Draft Records, 1940-1945 (Box 5, Folder 38A)
    Restricted material
  - Economic Policy, 1943-1944 (Box 5, Folder 39)
  - Economic Policy, 1945 (Box 5, Folder 39A)
  - Educational Division of Inter-American Educational Foundation, 1939-1946 (Box 5, Folder 40)
  - Executive Orders, 1940-1945 (Box 5, Folder 41)
  - Files, 1948-1976 (Box 5, Folder 42)
  - Film Contracts, 1942-1945 (Box 6, Folder 43)
  - Forrestal, James, 1940-1941 (Box 6, Folder 44)
  - Hull, Cordell and NAR, 1943-1944 (Box 6, Folder 45)
  - Inter-American Conferences, 1942-1947 (Box 6, Folder 46)
  - Inter-American System, 1942-1945 (Box 6, Folder 47)
  - Institute of Inter-American Affairs, 1942-1943 (Box 6, Folder 48)
    Related Archival Materials note
    See also: NAR Projects, Box 91
  - Jennings, Dwight D., 1944-1946 (Box 6, Folder 49)
  - Latin American Newsletter, 1941-1942 (Box 6, Folder 50)
  - Lockwood, John E., 1944 (Box 6, Folder 51)
  - Lozada, Enrique, 1942-1944 (Box 6, Folder 52)
  - Lozada, Enrique, 1945 (Box 7, Folder 53)
  - Mexican American Commission for Economic Cooperation (MAFEC), 1943-1945 (Box 7, Folder 54)
  - Mexican Water Treaty, 1944-1945 (Box 7, Folder 55)
  - Motion Picture Division, 1941-1944 (Box 7, Folder 56)
  - Motion Picture Division - Walt Disney Studio Survey of Literacy (Box 7, Folder 56A)
  - OEW-BEW-CIAA Relations, 1941-1944 (Box 7, Folder 57)
  - Office of Inter-American Affairs - Audits, 1948-1949 (Box 7, Folder 58)
  - Outlines, for Meetings, 1941-1950 (Box 7, Folder 59)
  - Washington, D.C.: CIAA. Five Aggregates of Charts. Outlines for Meetings., 1941-1956; GRAPH (Quantity 5) (Drawer D 15, Folder 1)
    Separated Materials note
    Separated from Series O, Box 7, Folder 59.
  - Pan American Day - Radios, 1942 (Box 7, Folder 60)
  - Philosophy and Objectives, 1942-1943 (Box 8, Folder 61)
  - Photostats, 1940-1945 (Box 8, Folder 62)
  - Post War Planning, 1943-1945 (Box 8, Folder 63)
  - Prencinradio, 1946 (Box 8, Folder 64)
  - Press, 1942-1954 (Box 8, Folder 65)
  - Press Division, 1942-1944 (Box 8, Folder 66)
  - Press Releases, October 1940 - March 1941 (Box 8, Folder 67)
  - Press Releases, April 1941 - June 1941 (Box 8, Folder 68)
  - Press Releases, July 1941 - May 1943 (Box 8, Folder 69)
  - CIAA and Other Government Departments - Releases, 1941-1942 (Box 9, Folder 70)
  - Proclaimed List, 1942-1944 (Box 9, Folder 71)
  - Propaganda, 1942-1944 (Box 9, Folder 72)
  - Radio Division, 1942-1944 (Box 9, Folder 73)
  - Reports, Miscellaneous (Box 9, Folder 74)
  - Reports, Miscellaneous (Box 9, Folder 75)
  - Roosevelt, Franklin D., Correspondence, 1939-1945 (Box 9, Folder 76)
  - Rowland History, 1944-1952 (Box 9, Folder 77)
  - Rubber, 1941-1943 (Box 10, Folder 78)
  - Senator Butler's Report to Congress, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 79)
  - Senator Butler's Report to Congress - Supporting Material, November 1943 (Box 10, Folder 79A)
  - Senator Butler's "Reader's Digest" Article, 1943-1944 (Box 10, Folder 80)
  - Butler Report - Reactions, 1943-1944 (Box 10, Folder 81)
  - Senator Kenneth McKeller, 1943-1946 (Box 10, Folder 82)
  - Speech Drafts for NAR and Senator Kenneth McKeller, 1943 (Box 10, Folder 83)
  - Report Drafts, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 84)
  - Report Drafts, Phase I, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 85)
  - Report Drafts, Phase II, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 86)
  - Snyder, Congressman J. Buell, 1945 (Box 11, Folder 87)
  - Stettinius, Edward and NAR, 1943-1946 (Box 11, Folder 88)
  - Survey of Economic Information, 1944 (Box 11, Folder 89)
  - Trade Agreements, 1940-1950 (Box 11, Folder 90)
  - Transportation, 1942 (Box 11, Folder 91)
  - Trips - South America, 1942 (Box 12, Folder 92)
  - Trips - Mexico, 1943 (Box 12, Folder 93)
  - Trips - Cleveland, 1944 (Box 12, Folder 94)
  - Trips - Central America, 1944 (Box 12, Folder 95)
  - Trips - Cuba, Haiti, Dominican Republic, and Venezuela, 1944 (Box 12, Folder 96)
  - Trips - Victor Borella Trip (Box 12, Folder 97)
  - Truman, Harry S. and NAR, 1945-1946 (Box 12, Folder 98)
  - U.S. Trade with Other American Republics, 1943-1947 (Box 12, Folder 99)
  - U.S. Trade with Other American Republics, 1943-1947 (Box 12, Folder 100)
  - Welles, Sumner, 1941-1942 (Box 12, Folder 101)
  - Yale Glee Club Tour, 1941 (Box 12, Folder 102)
  - CIAA Administrative Manual, 1944 (Box 13, Folder 103)
  - Surveys by Walt Disney Studios, 1940-1945 (Box 13, Folder 104)
  - Washington Publications and Printed Material
    - Reactions to Visit by Vice President Henry A. Wallace, 1943 (Box 13, Folder 105)
    - Rowland History Manuscript, Chapters 1-4, 1946 (Box 14, Folder 106)
    - Rowland History Manuscript, Chapters 6-12, 1946 (Box 14, Folder 107)
    - Rowland History Manuscript, Chapters 13-14, 1946 (Box 14, Folder 108)
    - Rowland History Manuscript, Chapters 15-18, 1946 (Box 14, Folder 109)
    - Rowland History Manuscript, Chapter 19, 1946 (Box 14, Folder 110)
    - Rowland History Manuscript, Chapters 20-22, 1946 (Box 14, Folder 111)
    - American News Letter, 1941-1943 (Box 15, Folder 112)
    - CIAA Summaries of Activities, 1941-1944 (Box 15, Folder 113)
    - Propaganda Literature (Box 15, Folder 114)
    - Propaganda Literature (Box 15, Folder 115)
    - Propaganda Literature (Box 16, Folder 116)
    - Propaganda Literature (Box 16, Folder 117)
    - Propaganda Literature (Box 16, Folder 118)
    - Propaganda Literature (Box 17, Folder 119)
    - Propaganda Literature (Box 17, Folder 120)
    - Propaganda Literature (Box 17, Folder 121)
    - Comic Book Histories (Box 17, Folder 122)
    - Susan Cable - Washington Stenograph Tablets (Box 17, Folder 123)
  - Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs (CIAA) Bound Volumes
    - Addresses of Nelson A. Rockefeller, 1940-1944 (Box 202, Volume 1)
      Brittle or damaged items, or materials otherwise in need of preservation care, may be closed to researchers at the discretion of the RAC Head of Archival Services/Head of Reference.
    - American Nations Series (Box 202, Volume 2)
    - American News Letters, 1941 July 29-1944 August 21 (Box 202, Volume 3)
    - Annual Reports of Corporations, 1942-1944 (Box 203, Volume 4)
    - Annual Reports of Institutions, 1945 (Box 203, Volume 5)
    - Bolivia, Journal of Dr. James D. Barger, 1944-1945 (Box 203, Volume 6)
    - Brazilian Air Mail Feature and Radio Service, 1944-1945 (Box 203, Volume 7)
    - Budget Hearings, 1941-1945 (Box 204, Volume 8)
    - Bureau of Latin America Research, 1944 March 28-1945 December 12 (Box 204, Volume 9)
    - Conference of Directors of Inter-American Centers (Box 204, Volume 10)
    - Coordination Committee Activities, 1944-1945 (Box 205, Volume 11)
    - Coordination Committee Activities, 1945 (Box 205, Volume 12)
    - Daily Content Directive, 1942-1943 (Box 205, Volume 13)
    - Daily Content Directive, 1944 (Box 206, Volume 14)
    - Daily Content Directive, 1945 January 1-December 31 (Box 206, Volume 15)
    - Daily Information Bulletin, 1942 (Box 207, Volume 16)
    - Daily Information Bulletin, Vol 1, 1943 (Box 207, Volume 17)
    - Daily Information Bulletin, Vol 2, 1943 (Box 208, Volume 18)
    - Daily Information Bulletin, Vol 3, 1943 (Box 208, Volume 19)
    - Daily Information Bulletin: Confidential, Vol 1, 1943 (Box 209, Volume 20)
    - Daily Information Bulletin: Confidential, Vol 2, 1943 (Box 209, Volume 21)
    - Daily Information Bulletin, Vol 1, 1944 (Box 210, Volume 22)
    - Daily Information Bulletin, Vol 2, 1944 (Box 210, Volume 23)
    - Daily Information Bulletin Part I, 1945 July 2-December 29 (Box 211, Volume 24)
    - Daily Information Bulletin Part II, 1945 January 1-June 30 (Box 211, Volume 25)
    - Daily Information Bulletin: Confidential, 1945 (Box 212, Volume 26)
    - Directory of the Field of Art (Box 212, Volume 27)
    - Directory of Institutions of Higher Learning (Box 212, Volume 28)
    - Education Memoranda on ?? (by Enrique S. de Lozada) (Box 212, Volume 29)
    - Emergency Rehabilitation Division, 1942-1943 (Box 212, Volume 30)
    - Exclusive Air Mail Feature Service, 1945 (Box 212, Volume 31)
    - Health and Sanitation Newsletter, 1942-1944 (Box 213, Volume 32)
    - Health and Sanitation Newsletter, 1945 (Box 213, Volume 33)
    - Human Defense of the Americans Basic Economy Department, 1942 (Box 213, Volume 34)
    - Inter-American Centers, Memoranda regarding, 1945 (Box 213, Volume 35)
    - Inter-American Economic News (Box 214, Volume 36)
    - Inter-American Education Foundation, Inc., Memoranda regarding (Box 214, Volume 37)
    - Inter-American Education Foundation, Inc., Minutes of (Box 214, Volume 38)
    - Inter-American Educational Foundation, Inc. Balance Sheet, 1943 November 30 (Box 214, Volume 39)
    - Inter-American Labor News, 1942-1944 (Box 214, Volume 40)
    - Labor Relations Reports, 1943-1945 (Box 214, Volume 41)
    - Monthly Political Reports, 1943-1944 (Box 215, Volume 42)
    - Newsreel: A Hundred Years of German Ambitions in Latin America (Box 215, Volume 43)
    - OIAA Trans., Vol 1 (Box 215, Volume 44)
    - OIAA Trans., Vol 2 (Box 215, Volume 45)
    - OIAA Trans., Vol 3 (Box 216, Volume 46)
    - Orinoco-Casiquiare-Negro Waterway Survey, Vol 1 (Box 216, Volume 47)
    - Orinoco-Casiquiare-Negro Waterway Survey, Vol 2 (Box 216, Volume 48)
    - Orinoco-Casiquiare-Negro Waterway Survey, Vol 3 (Box 217, Volume 49)
    - English Pamphlets (Box 218, Volume 50)
    - Spanish Pamphlets with Index, Vol 1 (Box 218, Volume 51)
    - Spanish Pamphlets with Index, Vol 2 (Box 219, Volume 52)
    - Spanish Pamphlets with Index, Vol 3 (Box 217, Volume 53)
    - Political Reports, 1945 (Box 219, Volume 54)
    - Political Reports, 1945 (Box 219, Volume 55)
    - Press Releases, 1940-1943 (Box 220, Volume 56)
    - Press and Radio Analysis, 1941 (Box 220, Volume 57)
    - Press and Radio Analysis, Vol 1, 1942 (Box 221, Volume 58)
    - Press and Radio Analysis, Vol 2, 1942 (Box 221, Volume 59)
    - Press and Radio Analysis, Vol 3, 1942 (Box 222, Volume 60)
    - Press and Radio Analysis, Vol 1, 1943 (Box 222, Volume 61)
    - Press and Radio Analysis, Vol 2, 1943 (Box 223, Volume 62)
    - Press and Radio Analysis, Vol 1, 1944 (Box 223, Volume 63)
    - Press and Radio Analysis, Vol 2, 1944 (Box 223, Volume 64)
    - Project Reports, 1942 (Box 224, Volume 65)
    - Project Reports, Vol 1, 1943 (Box 225, Volume 66)
    - Project Reports, Vol 2, 1943 (Box 226, Volume 67)
    - Project Reports, Vol 1, 1944 (Box 227, Volume 68)
    - Project Reports, Vol 2, 1944 (Box 225, Volume 69)
    - Propaganda Analysis, 1945 (Box 228, Volume 70)
    - Radio Division, 1945 September (Box 228, Volume 71)
    - Radio Division: Charts and Posters (Box 228, Volume 72)
    - Regional Division Reports, 1942 (Box 229, Volume 73)
    - Register of Visitors to Other American Republics, 1942-1944 (Box 229, Volume 74)
    - Register of Visitors from Other American Republics, 1942 (Box 230, Volume 75)
    - Register of Visitors from Other American Republics, 1943 (Box 230, Volume 76)
    - Register of Visitors from Other American Republics, 1944 (Box 231, Volume 77)
    - Register of Visitors from Other American Republics, Vol 1, 1945 January 1 - June 4 (Box 232, Volume 78)
    - Register of Visitors from Other American Republics, Vol 2, 1945 July 5- December 20 (Box 232, Volume 79)
    - Report on Conference of Leaders of Inter-American Activities in the United States, 1944 November (Box 233, Volume 80)
    - Social Surveys (Box 233, Volume 81)
    - Special Content Directives, 1942-1944 (Box 233, Volume 82)
    - Special Feature Material for Coordination Committees, 1944-1946 (Box 234, Volume 83)
    - Special Feature Service, 1945 (Box 234, Volume 84)
    - Special Feature Labor Service, 1945 (Box 234, Volume 85)
    - Special Political Reports, 1942-1943 (Box 235, Volume 86)
    - Special Political Reports, 1944 (Box 235, Volume 87)
    - Weekly Digest of Periodicals, 1943 (Box 235, Volume 88)
    - Weekly Digest of Periodicals, 1944 (Box 236, Volume 89)
    - Weekly Digest of Periodicals, 1945 (Box 236, Volume 90)
    - Weekly Economic Bulletin, 1943 (Box 236, Volume 91)
    - Weekly Economic Bulletin, 1944 (Box 237, Volume 92)
    - Weekly Economic Bulletin, 1945 (Box 237, Volume 93)
    - Weekly Political Report, 1942 (Box 238, Volume 94)
    - Weekly Report on Activities, 1942 (Box 239, Volume 95)
    - Weekly Report on Activities, 1943 (Box 239, Volume 96)
    - Weekly Report on Activities, 1944 (Box 240, Volume 97)
    - Weekly Report on Activities, 1945 (Box 240, Volume 98)
    - Weekly Review of Axis Broadcasts, 1942-1944 (Box 240, Volume 99)
  - Coordinator of Inter-American Affairs (CIAA) Bound Charts
    - CIAA (Box 241, Volume 1)
    - CIAA Miscellaneous (Box 241, Volume 2)
    - Argentina, Chile (Box 241, Volume 3)
    - Bolivia, Paraguay, Peru (Box 242, Volume 4)
    - Brazil, Uruguay (Box 242, Volume 5)
    - Colombia, Ecuador, Venezuela (Box 242, Volume 6)
    - Cuba, Dominican Republic, Haiti, Puerto Rico (Box 243, Volume 7)
    - Central America, Mexico (Box 243, Volume 8)
    - Hemisphere Index (Box 243, Volume 9)
- Assistant Secretary of State for American Republic Affairs, December 1944-August 1945; 2; 2 Cubic Feet
  Topics addressed in this subseries include the Inter-American Conference on Problems of War and Peace held in Mexico City in February 1945 and the United Nations Conference on International Organization held in San Francisco in April 1945.
  - Assistant Secretaries of State Bill, 1944-1945 (Box 18, Folder 124)
  - Letters of Congratulations to NAR (A-B), 1944-1945 (Box 18, Folder 125)
  - Letters of Congratulations to NAR (C-F), 1944-1945 (Box 18, Folder 126)
  - Letters of Congratulations to NAR (G-K), 1944-1945 (Box 18, Folder 127)
  - Letters of Congratulations to NAR (L-P), 1944-1945 (Box 18, Folder 128)
  - Letters of Congratulations to NAR (Q-Z), 1944-1945 (Box 18, Folder 129)
  - Letters re: NAR's Resignation (A-E), 1945 (Box 19, Folder 130)
  - Letters re: NAR's Resignation (F-L), 1945 (Box 19, Folder 131)
  - Letters re: NAR's Resignation (M-Z), 1945 (Box 19, Folder 132)
  - General, April 1944 - April 1945 (Box 19, Folder 133)
  - General, May - July, 1945 (Box 19, Folder 134)
  - General, August 1945 - April 1947 (Box 19, Folder 135)
  - Argentina, December 1944 - March 1945 (Box 19, Folder 136)
  - Argentina, General, April 1945 - May 1945 (Box 20, Folder 137)
  - Argentina, General, June - August 1945 (Box 20, Folder 138)
  - Argentina - NAR Analysis, 1944-1945 (Box 20, Folder 139)
  - Argentina - NAR Boston Speech, 1945 (Box 20, Folder 140)
  - Argentina - NAR Boston Speech, 1945 (Box 20, Folder 141)
  - Mexico City Conference, General, February 1944 - February 1945 (Box 20, Folder 142)
  - Mexico City Conference, General, February 1945 - October 1946 (Box 20, Folder 143)
  - Mexico City Conference, General, 1945 (Box 20, Folder 144)
  - Mexico City Conference - Printed Material, 1945 (Box 21, Folder 145)